Guide to the New York City Central Labor Council Photographs Collection PHOTOS.020
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
New York City Central Labor Council Photographs
Bulk, 1970-1989
circa 1940-1997, (Bulk circa 1970-1989)
PHOTOS.020
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
15.25 linear feet 24 boxes
The Central Trades and Labor Council of the American Federation of Labor merged with the New York City Congress of Industrial Organizations Council on February 19, 1959 to form the New York City Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO. The Council is an organization comprised of nearly 400 local union affiliates. The collection consists of approximately 8,200 mostly 8x10 black and white glossy prints, spanning the 1940s through the late 1990s, with the bulk dating from the 1970s and 1980s. Major areas covered by the collection include demonstrations by Council affiliates on various issues, and annual Council activities and events, such as the New York City Labor Day Parade. The principal photographers are Sam Reiss, Alexander Archer, Dan Miller, Jules Geller, and Mildred Gross.
(3x5, 5x7, 8x10 photographic prints; b&w & color)
AFL-CIO. New York City Central Labor Council.
Provenance
Donated by New York City Central Labor Council in several installments, beginning in July 1986.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Central Trades and Labor Council of the American Federation of Labor merged with the New York City Congress of Industrial Organizations Council on February 19, 1959 to form the New York City Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO. This followed the earlier merger (on December 9, 1958) of the New York State's AFL & CIO.
The New York City Central Labor Council is an organization comprised of nearly 400 local union affiliates. It only acts on local activities and concerns. It issues no statements on AFL-CIO policy and does not participate in its local affiliates and their parent organizations. Its purpose, according to its constitution, is to further the rights of workers to organize in unions and bargain collectively; to advocate legislation which is beneficial to workers and oppose that which is not; to correct abuses and to insure the workers their just rights. It also has more social and political purposes: to help all people who work for a living improve their working conditions and raise their standard of living; preserve their rights to act together for mutual aid and advancement; further the cause of unions; strengthen civil rights. It acts as the central force, providing assistance and education through its various committees and councils.
The regular activities of the New York City Central Labor Council are directed by its executive officers, Executive Board, and Delegates' Council meetings. The planning and execution of programs and conferences are conducted by various standing and special committees. These committees are composed of members from affiliated local unions, each with officers and advisory consulting staffs. They are responsible for specific programs and conferences. An important special committee is the Labor Day Parade Committee.
Harry Van Arsdale was elected the president of the Central Trades and Labor Council of the AFL in 1957. With the merger in 1959 he became the President of the Central Labor Council. During his presidency (1957-1986), the council established many diverse committees and programs such as the Rehabilitation Council (1963), Hispanic Labor Committee (1970), and the Black Trade Unionist Leadership Committee (1972). The Council was also instrumental in the founding of the Harry Van Arsdale Jr. Center for Labor Studies, in 1971, at Empire State College, State University of New York, to further labor education.
Upon Harry Van Arsdale's demise in 1986, his son, Thomas Van Arsdale was elected to the post of president.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of approximately 8,200 mostly 8x10 black and white glossy prints. Many were shot for potential use in Labor Chronicle, the Council's newspaper (published between the 1960s and early 1980s) and other Council publications.
The images span the 1940s through the late 1990s, although the bulk of them date from the 1970s and 1980s. Major areas within the collection include demonstrations by Council affiliates on various issues, and annual Council activities and events, such as the New York City Labor Day Parade, or the Council's annual Lincoln's Birthday Dinner, which features the bestowal of Annual Distinguished Services Awards on four trade unionists. This event is well-represented in the collection as are many of the Council's special committees.
Individuals are also well-represented, both in portraits and group shots. These include the presidents of the various locals that are represented on the Council, Executive Board members, and of course, the officers of the Council. The officers seen most often are: Harry Van Arsdale, President; Harry Avrutin, Secretary; Morris Iushewitz, Secretary (Avrutin's immediate predecessor); and William Bowe, Treasurer. Of particular interest, the collection also includes numerous photographs of many major New York City and New York State political figures and office-holders, from the 1940s onwards, shown posed with Council members or other labor leaders at events such as the New York City Labor Day Parade. These include mayors Robert F. Wagner, Jr., Abraham Beame, Edward Koch, Rudolph Giuliani, and governors Mario Cuomo and George Pataki.
The principal photographers in the collection (whose credit lines may be seen stamped on the back of many of the images).are Sam Reiss, Alexander Archer, Dan Miller, Jules Geller, and Mildred Gross.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically within each series and subseries.
Organized into 13 series:
I. Organization
II. Affiliates
III. Services
IV. Events
V. Chronological
VI. Portraits, Individuals
VII. Parades
VIII. Demonstrations
IX. Electoral Politics
X. Other Organizations
XI. Copy Negatives
XII. Oversized Prints
XIII. Unprocessed
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York City Central Labor Council Collection (Wagner 049)
Archer, Alexander; Avrutin, Harry; Bowe, William--Portraits.; Geller, Jules.; Gross, Mildred.; Iushewitz, Morris. -- |v Portraits; Labor chronicle.; Miller, Dan.; Reiss, Sam.; Van Arsdale, Harry, 1905-1986. -- |v Portraits; Black-and-white negatives.; Black-and-white photographs.; Collective bargaining.; Demonstrations |z New York (State) |z New York |v Pictorial works.; Industrial hygiene |x Law and legislation.; Labor Day |v Pictorial works.; Labor leaders |z New York (State) |z New York |v Portraits.; Labor union meetings |v Pictorial works.; Labor union members |z United States.; Labor unions |x Congresses and conventions |v portraits.; Labor unions |x Political activity |x Law and legislation.; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York (N.Y.); Photographic prints.
- Series I: ORGANIZATION
  - Subseries A. History and Predecessor Organizations
    - CIO – NYC COUNCIL, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - COUNCIL MERGER, Jan 13, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B. Central Labor Council Elections
    - INSTALLATION of OFFICERS – [NYC – Central Labor Council?], Dec 16, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - SWEARING IN, Dec 20, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - ELECTIONS, Mar 20, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B. Central Labor Council Elections
    - Sub-Subseries 1) Executive Board
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Mar 18, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Jul 13, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Sep 21, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Sep 20, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Jan 17, 1974 (Box 1, Drawer 10)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Apr 18, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Dec 19, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Mar 26, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Aug 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Nov 20, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Sep 16, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Dec 16, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, May 19, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Aug 17, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Dec 21, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Jul 19, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Nov 20, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, Apr 16, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETING, May 6, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Sub-Subseries 2) Other
      - MEETINGS – Miscellaneous – Mostly unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - ADVISORY COUNCIL – LABOR COLLEGE MEETING, Jun 14, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - ADIVSORY COUNCIL, Sep 7, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - ADVISORY COUNCIL MEETING, Feb 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - CENSUS MEETING, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE COMMITTEE MEETING, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE COMMITTEE MEETING, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - JOBS FOR YOUTH, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - MANPOWER COMMITTEE MEETING, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - SAVE OUR SCHOOLS – AD HOC COMMITTEE, May 1, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - SHORTER WORK WEEK COMMITTEE, ca.1950 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Subseries D. Committees
    - Sub-Subseries 1) Black Trade Unionists Labor Committee
      - BLACK TRADE UNIONISTS LEADERSHIP COMMITTEE DINNER, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - BTULC –DINNER, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - BTULC –DINNER, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - BTULC –DINNER, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - BTULC –DINNER, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - BTULC –DINNER, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - BTULC –DINNER, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Sub-Subseries 2) Hispanic Labor Committee
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – AWARDS, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - CONFERENCE – HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - SPANISH LABOR COMMMITTEE – MEETING – See also: HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE, Feb 5, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – DINNER, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – DINNER?, Jan 11, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – ENDORSES GOV. CAREY, Oct 26, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – CONFERENCE, Apr 16, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – DINNER, Dec 18, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – DINNER, Dec 2, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - HISPANIC LABOR COMMITTEE – DINNER, Nov 24, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Sub-Subseries 3) Interim Organization
      - INTERIM ORGANIZATION, Dec 27, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - INTERIM ORGANIZATION – STEERING COMMITTEE, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Sub-Subseries 4) Non-Partisan (Boro and County)
      - [non-partisan Boro Committees? – Elections], ca.1969 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - NON-PARTISAN BORO COMMITTEE, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - NON-PARTISAN COUNTY COMMITTEE ELECTIONS, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - NON-PARTISAN – 5 COUNTY COMMITTEES, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - NON-PARTISAN – 5 COUNTY COMMITTEES, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - NON-PARTISAN – 5 COUNTY COMMITTEES, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - NON-PARTISAN – 5 COUNTY COMMITTEES, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Subseries E. Conventions
    - Sub-Subseries 1) AFL-CIO
      - CONVENTION – AFL-CIO, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - CONVENTION – AFL-CIO, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - CONVENTION – AFL-CIO, Nov 22, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - CONVENTION – AFL-CIO, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - CONVENTION – AFL-CIO, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - CONVENTION – AFL-CIO, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Sub-Subseries 2) New York State AFL-CIO
      - CONVENTION – New York State AFL-CIO, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - CONVENTION – New York State AFL-CIO, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Subseries F. Conferences
    - CONFERENCES – Miscellaneous unidentified and undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - CONFERENCE – UNEMPLOYMENT, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - CONFERENCE – EDUCATION, May 21, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - CONFERENCE – DRUG ABUSE, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - CONFERENCE – IMPORTS, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - CONFERENCE – NATIONAL HEALTH INSURANCE, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - CONFERENCE – PAYABLE TAX, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - CONFERENCE – UNITED ITALIAN-AMERICAN LABOR COUNCIL, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - CONFERENCE – INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - CONFERENCE – NEW YORK WOMEN’S TRADE UNION, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - CONFERENCE – HELP FOR UNEMPLOYED, Mar 21, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - CONFERENCE – EDUCATION, Aug 10, 1978-Aug 13, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - CONFERENCE – JEWISH LABOR COMMITTEE, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - CONFERENCE – EDUCATION, Jun 9, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - CONFERENCE – ROOSEVELT CENTENARY, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Subseries G. Delegates
    - DELEGATES MEETING, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - DELEGATES MEETING, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - DELEGATES MEETING, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - DELEGATES MEETING, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - DELEGATES MEETING, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - DELEGATES MEETING, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - DELEGATES MEETING – VISIT COUNCIL HEADQUARTERS, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - DELEGATES MEETING – VISIT COUNCIL HEADQUARTERS, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 92)
- Series II: AFFILIATES
  - Miscellaneous Affiliates, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - CONVENTION – COUNCIL SUPERVISORS + ADMINISTRATORS – AFL-CIO, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - ACTORS EQUITY – HEARING, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - TRANSPORT WORKERS UNION – LOCAL 100 MEMBERSHIP MEETING, Mar 1973 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - SCHOLARSHIP – Local 23-25, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 97)
- Series III: SERVICES
  - Subseries A. Educational Programs
    - Sub-Subseries 1) ILR (School of Industrial and Labor Relations—Cornell University)
      - RISLEY’S CLASS – VISITS CLC, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - RISLEY’S CLASS – VISITS CLC, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Sub-Subseries 2) Empire State College
      - EMPIRE COLLEGE, undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - LABOR COLLEGE, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - LABOR COLLEGE, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – COLLECTIVE BARGAINING CLASS – AP., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - LABOR COLLEGE DINNER, May 1975 (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - LABOR COLLEGE DINNER, Sep 1976 (Box 3, Folder 105)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – FIRST GRADUATION, Sep 3, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 106)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – GRADUATION, Sep 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – GRADUATION, Jun 25, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 108)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – GRADUATION, Jun 24, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 109)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – GRADUATION, Jun 13, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – GRADUATION, Jun 25, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 111)
      - LABOR COLLEGE – SCHOLARSHIP AWARD CEREMONY, Dec 1, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Sub-Subseries 3) Wagner Summer School
      - WAGNER SUMMER SCHOOL, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 113)
      - WAGNER SUMMER SCHOOL, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 114)
      - WAGNER SUMMER SCHOOL, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Subseries B. Camps
    - CAMP SEBAGO, undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - CAMP WABENAKI, undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Subseries C. Social Services/ Community Services
    - PERFORMING ARTS + CULTURAL PROJECT, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - RED CROSS – LABOR SEMINAR, May 1975 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - RED CROSS – LABOR SEMINAR, May 1977 (Box 4, Folder 120)
- Series IV: EVENTS
  - Subseries A. Central Labor Council Annual Events
    - Sub-Subseries 1) Community
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 123)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 124)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 127)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 128)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - COMMUNITY SERVICE INSTITUTE, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Sub-Subseries 2) Conference—Civil Rights
      - CONFERENCE – CIVIL RIGHTS, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - CONFERENCE – CIVIL RIGHTS, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - CONFERENCE – CIVIL RIGHTS, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - CONFERENCE – CIVIL RIGHTS, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Sub-Subseries 3) Labor Day Mass
      - LABOR DAY MASS – ST. PATRICK’S CATHEDRAL, Sep 6, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - LABOR DAY MASS, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - LABOR DAY MASS, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - LABOR DAY MASS, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - LABOR DAY MASS, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - LABOR DAY MASS, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 140)
      - LABOR DAY MASS, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Sub-Subseries 4) Labor Day Street Fair
      - LABOR DAY – STREET FAIR, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Sub-Subseries 5) Lacey, Martin Scholarship
      - LACEY, MARTIN – SCHOLARSHIP, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - LACEY, MARTIN – SCHOLARSHIP, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 144)
      - LACEY, MARTIN – SCHOLARSHIP, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - LACEY, MARTIN – SCHOLARSHIP, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 146)
      - LACEY, MARTIN – SCHOLARSHIP, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Sub-Subseries 6) Lincoln’s Birthday Dinner
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 148)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 149)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 150)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 151)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 152)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 153)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 154)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 155)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 156)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 157)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 158)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 159)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 160)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 161)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 162)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 163)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 164)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 165)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 166)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 167)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 168)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 169)
      - LINCOLN’S BIRTHDAY DINNER, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - Sub-Subseries 7) Workers Memorial Day
      - WORKER S MEMORIAL DAY (3rd Annual), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - Subseries B. Awards
    - AWARDS-VARIOUS DATES AND UNDATED (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - DUBINSKY, DAVID – WEEK, Oct 12, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - DAN, DR. PHAN QUANG – RECEPTION, May 22, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - ISRAEL’S 20th ANNIVERSARY, Jun 11, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - BOWE DINNER, Jun 12, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - CAMPAIGN – UNITED STATES SAVINGS BOND, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - DIEHL DINNER, Jun 12, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - MEANY DINNER – IRISH HISTORICAL SOCIETY, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - PLUNKETT, CHRIS – BON VOYAGE to ISRAEL, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - ISRAEL UNITED, Nov 1973 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - SERVICE EMPLOYEES – DINNERS, 1973, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - BURNELL – SWEARING IN, Jan 29, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - SENATE HEARING ON UNEMPLOYMENT, Mar 1975 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - DRUG ABUSE PRESS CONFERENCE, May 1975 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - “COLLECTIVE BARGAINING” GEORGE SEGAL, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - CONTRACT for JOB PLACEMENT PROGRAM (CETA), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - [Bicentennial Event], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - BICENTENNIAL – “I PAID MY DUES” BICENTENNIAL ENTERTAINMENT, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - MEANY AWARD, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - JEWISH LABOR COMMITTEE DINNER, Jan 12, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - BURNELL INSTALLATION, Mar 1, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - LEWIS HINE PHOTO EXHIBITION, Mar 10, 1977May 15, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - BUKOVSY LUNCHEON, Dec 10, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - TESTIMONIAL DINNER HONORING REVEREND PHILIP A. CAREY, 1977-Nov 15, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - TAIWANESE DELEGATION, Jul 19, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - RANDOLPH, PHILIP – IN MEMORIUM, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - METROPOLITAN MUSEUM OF ART – CHINESE GARDEN COURT, Jan 1980 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - CENTENIAL LABOR CELEBRATION, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - MEANY PUBLIC SCHOOL, ca.1981 (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - ADULT LEARNING, Mar 17, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - DONAHUE SPEAKS, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 202)
    - MANN, Michael – TRIBUTE, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - MEDICAL LABOR SEMINAR, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - STATUE OF LIBERTY, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 205)
- Series V: CHRONOLOGICAL
  - 1940s, undated (Box 7, Folder 206)
  - 1940s (?), undated (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - 1950s, undated (Box 7, Folder 208)
  - 1950s (?), undated (Box 7, Folder 209)
  - 1960s, undated (Box 7, Folder 210)
  - 1960s (?) 1 of 2, undated (Box 7, Folder 211)
  - 1960s (?) 2 of 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - 1970s - 1 of 2 folders, undated (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - 1970s – 2 of 2 folders, undated (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - 1970s (?) – 1 of 3 folders, undated (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - 1970s (?) 2 of 3 folders, undated (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - 1970s (?) 3 of 3 folders, undated (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - 1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - 1980s (?) 1 of 2 folders, undated (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - 1980s (?) 2 of 2 folders, undated (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - 1990s, undated (Box 9, Folder 221)
- Series VI: PORTRAITS/INDIVIDUALS
  - AVRUTIN, HARRY, undated (Box 9, Folder 222)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous – A, undated (Box 9, Folder 223)
  - BEAME, MAYOR ABRAHAM, undated (Box 9, Folder 224)
  - BOWE, WILLIAM, undated (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: B, undated (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - CHAVEZ, CAESAR, undated (Box 9, Folder 227)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: C, undated (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - DAVIS, SAMMY, Jr., undated (Box 9, Folder 229)
  - DUBINSKY, DAVID, undated (Box 9, Folder 230)
  - DURST, DAVID, undated (Box 9, Folder 231)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: D+E, undated (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - FELDMAN, SANDRA, undated (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: F, undated (Box 9, Folder 234)
  - GARRAHAN, CHARLES, undated (Box 9, Folder 235)
  - GUINAN, MATHEW, undated (Box 9, Folder 236)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: G, undated (Box 9, Folder 237)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: H, undated (Box 9, Folder 238)
  - IUSHEWITZ, MORRIS, undated (Box 9, Folder 239)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: I+J, undated (Box 9, Folder 240)
  - KENNEDY, ROBERT F, undated (Box 10, Folder 241)
  - KING, MARTIN LUTHER, Jr., undated (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: K, undated (Box 10, Folder 243)
  - LAWE, JOHN, undated (Box 10, Folder 244)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: L, undated (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - MEANY, GEORGE, undated (Box 10, Folder 246)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: M, undated (Box 10, Folder 247)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: N, undated (Box 10, Folder 248)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: O, undated (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - POLLACK, CECILIA (NEW YORK TEACHERS UNION), undated (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - POTOFSKY, JACOB, undated (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - Portraits – Miscellaneous: P, undated (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - QUILL, MICHAEL, undated (Box 10, Folder 253)